https://github.com/probinso

#### Personal Statement

I have 7+ years experience, solving increasingly difficult problems with software. My projects span products and research including data pipelines/management, medical informatics, programming languages, computer securities, audio, image, and text processing. I have developed strong interests in scientific computing, information retrieval, machine learning, and education.

#### Persistent Experience :

C, C++ Python Linux TDD

Git R, dplyr BTrX Ticketing Systems

# Work Experience \_

#### Graduate Research with ACO - Marine Acoustics Engineer

(continuing)

Researched deep unsupervised anomaly detectors, for sane indexing of 10 year audio track Developed ACOio, an intuitive ACO track explorer, to rejuvenate data access for researchers Developed principled audio processing and noise-suppression, focused on marine bioacoustics

Technologies: Python, ACOio, tensorflow, scipy.signal, Jupyter

- Data Science Technical Expert Thinkful (Part Time) Jan. 2019 - present Advised career transitioners in mastery of professional and data science topics Provided safe environment for 1:1 training and instruction in a remote-first setting

- Graduate Data Science Intern June 2018 - Sept. 2018 NASA Jet Propulsion Lab Designed & developed Expert Modeling/Recommender System, by extending the Author-Topic-Model Developed and specified program from use-case meetings with top NASA/JPL employees Implemented stable/principled text normalization, tokenization, and model evaluation Open Source contributions to the gensim's natural language processing library

Technologies: Python, nltk, gensim, pyLDAvis, pandas, Jupyter

#### - Research Assistant OHSU Fair Neuroimaging Lab

Oct. 2017 - June 2018

Contributed to workflows and analytics tools for studying Microbiome populations Supported research on developing brains, including ABCD, and several ADHD/ASD studies Developed processing pipeline and audit tools for reported data and FMRI images

Technologies: Python, Bash, R, neo4j, ponyorm, stan, GitLab, Docker

### Contractor/Consultant

#### RGB Optics / C&W Energy USA (Part Time)

Nov. 2015 - Aug. 2018

Developed custom photo image processing tools for low cost spectral profile analysis Authored educational material in light pollution's effect on economy, biology, and technology Provided live technology tutorials and consulting on optimization and image processing

June 2016 - Sept. 2016 ComScore

Worked to support large, custom, memory mapped, data store for demographic analysis Melinae March 2016

Setup infrastructure in AWS to enable secure & sustainable remote-first workflow

Provided hands on training in Python and R to industry professionals Technologies: Python, numpy, skimage, R, AWS, PostgreSQL, Perl, C++, Jira, ZenHub

- Research Engineer Galois Inc. April 2014 - Dec 2015

Developed processing pipelines and workflows to enable evaluator work for DARPA programs Produced biannual quantitative and qualitative reports on for DARPA and language developers Participated in programs sharing new technologies to research and industry professionals

Technologies: Python, SLURM, Scala, Figaro, Chimpy, Docker, Jira, Basecamp

- Software Development Engineer Dec. 2012 - July 2013  ${ t EMC}^2$  Isilon Storage

Brought to schedule a lagging anchor release feature in approximately 5 months Designed and developed password manager to support Data At Rest Encryption Wrote unit tests using libcheck to attain > 80% code coverage

Technologies: C, C++, Python, SQLite, Subversion, FreeBSD, OpenSSL

# Neato Projects \_

Multiple Myeloma Clinical Trials custom named-entity boosted topic model numpy, Python Topic modeling and applications, a presentation for non-statisticians beamer, MTEX Workshop collaborative introduction to GitHub and slides markdown, bash, github.api Morphological Watersheding Algorithms pyspark, numpy, ndimage, Python Relevance Vector Machine Information Retrieval Cluster/Rank Demo Harness flask, numpy, nltk, sklearn, Python Gene Data Breast Cancer Drug Predictor R, caret Distributed Fully Homomorphic Encryption System Hadoop, Sagemath Concurrent Elliptic Curve Cryptography Module Sagemath, Erlang Multilingual Analysis of Subordinating and Coordinating Conjunctions R, Perl AdaRailz Concurrent Model Train Control System Ada

# Education

# Oregon Health Science University

**CSLU** 

Computer Science MSc 2016 - present

Expected Graduation: Sept. 2019

#### Courses :

\* Advanced Topics in Machine Learning Deep Learning Machine Learning Artificial Intelligence Statistical Methods Univariate Statistical Analysis Analysis of Sequences

- \* Natural Language Processing
- \* Advanced Topics in Signal Processing Speech Signal Processing Problem Solving with Large Clusters Image Processing Information Retrieval Computing Ethics

# Western Washington University

Unix Software Development

Computer Science BS, Mathematics Minor June 2012

Computer Science

# Courses :

Windows Software Development Operating Systems Computer Networks Software Project Requirements Analysis Software Project Design Software Project Implementation Analysis of Algorithms

Linear/Non-Linear Data Structures Discrete Structures Formal Languages/Automata Programming Languages Concurrent Programming Computer Organization I/II Probability and Statistical Inference Object-Oriented Programming in C++

## Electives :

Homomorphic Encryption Systems Cryptography & Elliptic Curves Artificial Intelligence Natural Language Processing Functional Programming Computer Graphics

Computer Architecture Number Theory Elementary Real Analysis Abstract Algebra Linear Algebra I/II Ordinary Differential Equations